NARDIN LACHOWSKI

Software Engineer

203-570-9066 nardin.lachowski@gmail.com Boston Metro, MA linkedin.com/in/nardinl nard1n.github.io

ABOUT

Results oriented Web Developer with over 6 years of experience spanning various product integrations and software implementation projects. Worked at fast-paced internet and software companies to develop strong organizational skills leading all phases of diverse technology initiatives. Enjoys building new features that contribute to improved user experience and can spend hours effortlessly debugging away. My skills are varied across frontend and backend technologies with my strong suit being Node.js, React, Express.js, and Next.js.

Technical Skills:

JavaScript(ES6+), React (Hooks, Router, Context API), Redux, Node.js/Express, HTML/CSS/SCSS, OOP, Functional Programming, Git, SQL (MySQL, Sequelize), NoSQL (MongoDB, Mongoose), Agile/Scrum Development, RESTful APIs, Authentication (Bcrypt, Express Session, JWTs), Microservices, Software design, Component Library Integration, Next.js, JSON, TDD (Jest), jQuery, XML, Python, AWS, Jira/Confluence

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Frontend Software Engineer

Known Point Technologies

04/2021 - Present Remote, MA

- Handles dynamic routing with React Router, increasing page-loading performance in a single-page environment to create a cohesive user experience while displaying multiple client views.
- · Bootstrap CSS elements (flexbox & grid) to create responsive designs, allow for modularization, and maintain a consistent layout
- Meets with the UX/UI, Product, and Engineering teams on a recurring basis utilizing an agile mindset for delivering, sustaining, and discussing the product roadmap with CTO
- Frequently tests application and coordinates bug bash sessions to review new releases for performance and usability. Adding any issues or bugs that arise onto the roadmap in a Kanban format

Implementations Technology Consultant

10/2019 - 07/2021

Paytronix Systems

Remote, MA

- Leads multifaceted product deployments of Enterprise and SMB clients as the sole project manager and technical consultant
- · Focuses on mitigating risks and technological dependencies in order to effectively decrease complexity and launch timelines
- Launched early clients with newly released restaurant integrated software while thoroughly documenting configurations and test plans resulting in better quality integrated restaurant software implementation process
- Handles large scale client demographic and financial data migrations from previous providers while setting data integrity QA initiatives to ensure financial accuracy and a seamless end user experience during a brand's transition between vendors
- Rapidly mastered new product offering to join a taskforce that aids in restaurant implementation efforts earlier in the pandemic

Client Integrations Engineer

CJ Affiliate

12/2018 - 10/2019 Westborough, MA

.....

- Managed the ELK (Elasticsearch, Logstash, and Kibana) cluster for centralized logging and collecting server metrics of integrations
- Introduced dashboards for integration deployment projects serving cross-functional visibility and improving team productivity
- · Responsible for quality assurance and testing to ensure deployments and improvements meet all requirements prior to launch
- Partnered with global advertisers across all verticals to deploy robust tracking solutions for ecommerce websites and mobile apps
- · Provided solutions to optimize the implementation of Google Tag Manager (GTM), Shopify, BigCommerce, and Magento

Product Support Analyst

04/2015 - 12/2018

Indeed.com

Stamford, CT

- Utilized SQL to thoroughly analyze common trends for determining behavior and impact on over 100m unique monthly visitors
- Extensive knowledge and monitoring of RESTful API integrations to ensure quality, page rendering, and performance
- Contributed to early GDPR risk assessments and privacy optimization initiatives which led to collaborations with Program Managers to integrate user forms on site for improved experience and user data security
- · Automated Client Satisfaction and Peer-to-Peer feedback programs with custom algorithms and Google Apps Script

OPEN SOURCE

Takeoff | takeoff123.herokuapp.com | github.com/nard1n/takeoff

- Employed Passport.js middleware with Jsonwebtokens(jwt) to promote secure user login experience
- Used React/Redux architecture with Material UI to minimize complexity and maintain a consistent code layout from developer to developer while keeping in mind further scalability.
- · Utilizes React Hooks to coordinate user flows without compromising scalability or efficiency

EDUCATION

Full Stack Development, Certificate University of Connecticut, School of Engineering **Bachelor of Science,** Biological Sciences, University of Connecticut